His whole life was a million-to-one shot.
Rocky is a drama film directed by John G. Avildsen.
Rocky Balboa is a Philadelphia club fighter who seems to be going nowhere.
But when a stroke of fate puts him in the ring with a world heavyweight champion, Rocky knows that it's his one
shot at the big time — a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity to go the distance and come out a winner!
Robert 'Rocky' Balboa, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Adrianna 'Adrian' Pennino, played by Talia Shire.
Paulie Pennino, played by Burt Young.
Apollo Creed, played by Carl Weathers.
Mickey Goldmill, played by Burgess Meredith.
George 'Miles' Jergens, played by Thayer David.
Rocky is a 1976 American independent sports drama film directed by John G.
Avildsen, written by and starring Sylvester Stallone.
It is the first installment in the Rocky franchise and also stars Talia
Shire, Burt Young, Carl Weathers, and Burgess Meredith.
In the film, Rocky Balboa (Stallone), a poor small-time club fighter and loanshark debt collector from Philadelphia, gets
an unlikely once in a lifetime shot at the world heavyweight championship held by Apollo Creed (Weathers).
Rocky entered development in March 1975, after
Stallone wrote the screenplay in three days.
It entered a complicated production process after Stallone refused to allow the film to be made without him in the lead role;
United Artists eventually agreed to cast Stallone after he rejected a six figure deal for the film rights.
Principal photography began in January 1976, with filming primarily held in Philadelphia; several
locations featured in the film, such as the Rocky Steps, are now considered cultural landmarks.
With an estimated production budget of under $1.1 million, Rocky popularized the rags to
riches and American Dream themes of sports dramas which preceded the film.
Rocky had its premiere in New York City on November 20, 1976, and was
released in the United States on December 3, 1976.
Rocky became the highest-grossing film of 1976, earning
approximately $225 million worldwide.
The film received critical acclaim for Stallone's writing, as well as the film's performances, direction, musical score, cinematography
and editing; among other accolades, it received ten Academy Award nominations and won three, including Best Picture.
It has been ranked by numerous publications as one of the greatest films of
all time, as well as one of the most iconic sports films ever.
Rocky and its theme song have become a pop-cultural phenomenon and
an important part of 1970s American popular culture.
In 2006, the Library of Congress selected Rocky for preservation in the United States National
Film Registry as being "culturally, historically or aesthetically significant".
The first sequel in the series, Rocky II, was released in 1979.
The film explores themes of underdog, philadelphia, pennsylvania,
transporter, love of one's life, italian american.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.